America's Most Wanted.
Public Enemies is a crime, history, drama film directed by Michael Mann.
Depression-era bank robber John Dillinger's charm and audacity endear him to much of
America's downtrodden public, but he's also a thorn in the side of J.
Edgar Hoover and the fledgling FBI.
Desperate to capture the elusive outlaw, Hoover makes Dillinger his first Public Enemy Number One
and assigns his top agent, Melvin Purvis, the task of bringing him in dead or alive.
John Dillinger, played by Johnny Depp.
Melvin Purvis, played by Christian Bale.
Billie Frechette, played by Marion Cotillard.
'Red' Hamilton, played by Jason Clarke.
Agent Carter Baum, played by Rory Cochrane.
J. Edgar Hoover, played by Billy Crudup.
Public Enemies is a 2009 American biographical crime drama film directed by Michael
Mann, who co-wrote the screenplay with Ronan Bennett and Ann Biderman.
It is an adaptation of Bryan Burrough's 2004 non-fiction book Public Enemies:
America's Greatest Crime Wave and the Birth of the FBI, 1933–34.
Set during the Great Depression, the film chronicles the final years of the notorious bank robber John Dillinger (Johnny Depp) as he is pursued by FBI agent Melvin Purvis (Christian Bale), Dillinger's relationship with Billie Frechette (Marion
Cotillard), as well as Purvis' pursuit of Dillinger's associates and fellow criminals John "Red" Hamilton (Jason Clarke), Homer Van Meter (Stephen Dorff), Harry Pierpont (David Wenham), and Baby Face Nelson (Stephen Graham).
Burrough originally intended to make a television miniseries about the Depression-era crime
wave in the United States, but decided to write a book on the subject instead.
Mann developed the project, and some scenes were filmed on location where they
occurred, though the film is not entirely historically accurate.
Public Enemies premiered in Chicago on June 19, 2009, and was
released on July 1, 2009, by Universal Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
$214.1 million worldwide against an $80–100 million budget.
The film explores themes of escape, gun, gangster, machinegun, horse race.
The tone is emotional.